Manschinger, Kurt and Grete Hartwig; Papers ger025
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Artistic Works, 1916-1984; 3; 10.94 cubic ft.
  - Sheet Music: Dreigroschenoperette (30 Songs, No.17), 1932 (Oversize 4, Folder 10)
  - Sheet Music: Eine Dame Telefoniert (30 Songs, No. 10), 1931 (Oversize 4, Folder 11)
  - Sheet Music: Ein Paar Neue Rekorde (30 Songs, No. 19), 1932 (Oversize 4, Folder 12)
  - Sheet Music: Elegie, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Sheet Music: Fruhe Lieder, 1924-1928 (Oversize 4, Folder 15)
  - Sheet Music: Gasthauspychologie (30 Songs, No.18), 1932 (Oversize 4, Folder 16)
  - Sheet Music: The Glow-Worm for Women's Voices and Piano, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 18)
  - Sheet Music: Hafenlied, 1935 (Oversize 4, Folder 17)
  - Sheet Music: The Hedgehog, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 19)
  - Sheet Music: Herr Bombardit (Der Imiboquo-Mibubribro, No. 6) (30 Songs, No. 4), Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 21)
  - Sheet Music: Hurdy-Gurdy Rhymes, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 20)
  - Sheet Music: Hymnische Suite, Undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Sheet Music: Ich Bin So Grenzenlos Allein, 1935 (Oversize 4, Folder 22)
  - Sheet Music: Im Herbst/In Autumn, Undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Sheet Music: Intros for Greta's "Scenes" and Special Medleys etc., Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 23)
  - Sheet Music: Italian Street Songs for Three Women's Voices and Piano, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 24)
  - Sheet Music: John Brown, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 25)
  - Sheet Music: Karntner G'muath, Undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Sheet Music: Letter From a Field Hospital, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 26)
  - Sheet Music: Looking for Rain Beaux (SSA), Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 27)
  - Sheet Music: Loose Page, July 1940, After The Fall of France, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 28)
  - Sheet Music: Lovely Evening (Quintet), Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 29)
  - Sheet Music: Mein Liebster fuhr Uber die Meere, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 30)
  - Sheet Music: Mille Fleurs, 1958; Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 31)
  - Sheet Music: Miscellaneous Music - Fragments and Unfinished (Not Originals), Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 32)
  - Sheet Music: Mondane Frau, 1935 (Oversize 4, Folder 33)
  - Sheet Music: Nelly Gray, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 34)
  - Sheet Music: Neurotic Songs, Undated (Oversize 4, Folder 35)
  - Sheet Music: Neuongarische Lyrik (30 Songs, No.11), 1931 (Oversize 4, Folder 36)
  - Sheet Music: Ordnnung Sliebende Madehen, 1937 January (Oversize 5, Folder 1)
  - Sheet Music: Oh, Dear! What Can The Matter Be? For Three Women's Voices, and Piano, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 2)
  - Sheet Music: Parole Aus Der Feine, 1942 April 15 (Oversize 5, Folder 3)
  - Sheet Music: Quintet for Cello by Ashley Vernon, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
  - Sheet Music: Quintet for Clarinet by Ashley Vernon, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
  - Sheet Music: Quintet for Horn by Ashley Vernon, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
  - Sheet Music: Quintet for Piano by Ashley Vernon, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 7)
  - Sheet Music: Quintet for Violin by Ashley Vernon, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 8)
  - Sheet Music: The Real Musetta (Parody), Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 9)
  - Sheet Music: The Reformed Drunkard, 1953; Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 10)
  - Sheet Music: Reklane - Schlage (4 Songs), 1929; 1937; Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 11)
  - Sheet Music: Rhapsody for Oboe (Master), Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 12)
  - Sheet Music: Russische Bauernhochzeit (30 Songs, No. 12), Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 13)
  - Sheet Music: Russischer Jahrmarkt (30 Songs, No. 24), 1932 (Oversize 5, Folder 14)
  - Sheet Music: Seeschlangenfox (30 Songs, No. 29), 1934 (Oversize 5, Folder 15)
  - Sheet Music: Sex-Appeal (30 Songs, No. 23), 1932 (Oversize 5, Folder 16)
  - Sheet Music: Sieben Gesange (Songs, No. 1-7), 1935 (Oversize 5, Folder 17)
  - Sheet Music: Soldier Songs, 1942 July 15 (Oversize 5, Folder 18)
  - Sheet Music: Song for Manner (30 Songs, No. 25), 1932 (Oversize 5, Folder 19)
  - Sheet Music: Telephone Scehe (From the Revue: (Is this Trip Necessary?), Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 20)
  - Sheet Music: Two Strawberries, 1945 (Oversize 5, Folder 21)
  - Sheet Music: Two Strawberries (Sheet Music), 1945 (Oversize 5, Folder 22)
  - Sheet Music: Tyrolese Romance, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 23)
  - Sheet Music: Und Pepik Gibit Mir Hubicku (30 Songs, No.8), 1931 (Oversize 5, Folder 24)
  - Sheet Music: Vor Und Zwischenspiel, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 25)
  - Sheet Music: Vorsicht (30 Songs, No. 6), 1931 (Oversize 5, Folder 26)
  - Sheet Music: Vorspiel (Der Imiboquo-Mibubribo, No. 1), Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 27)
  - Sheet Music: Wachterruf (30 Songs, No. 2), Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 28)
  - Sheet Music: Warning, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 29)
  - Sheet Music: Weep Not, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 30)
  - Sheet Music: When Johnny Comes Marching Home, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 31)
  - Sheet Music: Wien, Was Fallt Denn Dir Nur Ein (30 Songs, No. 26), 1933 (Oversize 5, Folder 32)
  - Sheet Music: Wo Kann Man Heut, 1930 (Oversize 5, Folder 33)
  - Sheet Music: Wochenschau Nr. 1, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 34)
  - Sheet Music: Wunsch (30 Songs, No. 5), 1931 (Oversize 5, Folder 35)
  - La Serva Padrona, Undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Short Stories: Autopsy of A Love Affair - English, 1971 February (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Short Stories: Collection of Unpublished Stories - German, 1917; 1941-1948; 1963-1964; Undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Short Stories: Dottie and Larry - 3 Stories, German, Undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Short Stories: "Ein Kleines Lied Und Eine Grasse Liebe", Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Short Stories: Greta Hartwig With Collaborator Else Frey - Ina Thal, 1941; 1952; 1960; Undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Short Stories: Greta Hartwig With Hilde Sidney, Undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Short Stories: Little Guest From Europe - English, Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Short Stories: Manhattan Miscellany, 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Short Stories: Mike Fink - German, Undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Short Stories: Original, 1942; Undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Short Stories: Professor Van Dyn, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Showcase Programs (Manschinger), 1957 October 13 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Short Stories: Punishment and Crime English, 1944; 1960; 1963; 1969 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Sketches, Undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Sketches: First Drafts and Incomplete, 1942; Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Skits: Buying a Pair of Shoes - English, Undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Skits: Chat Across The Fence for Two Women - English, Undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Skits: Doctor, Doctor (Music Opt.), 1961 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Skits: Eve in Paradise, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Skits: Grease Paint- English, Undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Skit: Hello Ben, How are You? For Two Men- English, Undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Skit: I Never Want to See Him Again Monologue - English, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Skit: The Impresario - Playlet (Abbreviated Version) - English, Undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Skits: Life of A Salesman, Undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Skits: Who was Murdered?, Undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Skit: Will Webster Propose - English, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Song: Aus Der Tiere, 1933; Undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Song Der Felt, Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 36)
  - Song: Vom Roten Wien, Undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Songs by Kurt Manschinger, 1976 May 11 (Lp 2)
  - Songs by Kurt Manschinger; Greta Hartwig, Voice; Kurt Manschinger, Piano, Undated (Reel 40)
  - Songs by Kurt Manschinger; Various Poets; Greta Hartwig, Voice with Piano; Rehearsal for Boston Program (Not Given), 1969 February 3 (Reel 20)
  - Songs of Kurt Manschinger (1 of 2), 1976 May 11 (Reel 60)
  - Songs of Kurt Manschinger (2 of 2), 1976 May 11 (Reel 61)
  - Songs of Kurt Manschinger, Master Original of Recording Session, 1976 May 11 (Reel 58)
  - Songs of Kurt Manschinger, Original Studio Copy, 1976 May 11 (Reel 59)
  - Songs of Kurt Manschinger, Out Takes, Rejected from Recording Session, 1976 May 11 (Reel 57)
  - Special Material: Commissioned Sold, 1958-1960; 1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Special Material: "Knitwits", 1960-1963; Undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Stage Direction, 1956-1957; 1969; Undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Students: Jan Owen, 1968; 1970-1972; Undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Students: Jan (Ruetz) DeGaetani, 1956; 1975; 1978-1979; Undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Student: Lilia Skala, 1951-1955; 1962-1971; 1975-1977; Undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Students: Marcia Rodd, 1964-1965; 1967-1973; 1977-1978; 1984; Undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Students: "Mrs. Hodghinson", 1965 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Students: Norma Glenn, 1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Students: Victor Brozani, 1965; Undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Students: Zelna Carmena, 1965-1966; 1968-1970; 1972-1975; Undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Submitted and Returned Works by Ashley Vernon, 1947-1971 (Card-file 1)
  - Teaching: Adirondack Center For Cultural and Creative Arts, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Teaching: Auditioning, Undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Teaching: Cornell Academy of Musical and Dramatic Arts, 1952; Undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Teaching: Juilliard School, 1952; Undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Teaching: Miscellaneous Material, 1952; 1970-1971; Undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Teaching: New York Ballet and Drama Centre, 1951-1952; Undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Teaching: New York College of Music, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Teaching: Ramblerny, 1961-1964; 1966; Undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Teaching: Stage Direction, 1952-1953; 1957-1958; 1965-1969; Undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Teaching: Voice Instruction, 1951; 1967; Undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - That is Jazz (30 Songs, No. 9), 1931 (Oversize 5, Folder 37)
  - Theodor Hartwig, Articles Manuscript, 1946; Undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Theodor Hartwig, An Appreciation in Freidenker, 1958 January (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Theodor Hartwig, "Fascism in German"/"Der Faschismus in Deutschland", 1933 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Theodor Hartwig, Memorial in Freidenker, 1958 March (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Theodor Hartwig, "Unverstandenes Leben" Manuscript, Undated (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - There was a Girl, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Three Songs of the Resistance, 1966 December (Reel 42)
  - Torment of Love, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Translation Sample, 1947; 1951; Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Underground Scorn, 1944; Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 38)
  - Untitled Libretto, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Variatidnen Uber Ein Deutsches Volkslied (30 Songs, No. 30), 1939; Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 39)
  - Viele Sind Stark, 1930; 1974; 1977; Undated (Oversize 5, Folder 40)
  - Vitamin Song, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - White Envelope - St Peter's Gate Cabaret Theatre, December, Greta's One Woman Show, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Wir, 1939 August (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Wilbur Broms and Jan Own "Shakespeare" Program, Contracts, etc., 1964; Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Works By Others, 1941; 1943; 1950; Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Works: Original Poems and Lyrics in German, 1916-1917; 1933-1939; 1949-1950; 1964-1971; Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Zeitgemesse Sorgen Einer Mondanen Frau, 1937 January (Oversize 5, Folder 41)
  - Zelda: A New Comedy Only Edited By Greta Hartwig, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)